The epic story of love and adventure in a lawless land.
Wyatt Earp is a western, drama, action film directed by Lawrence Kasdan.
From Wichita to Dodge City, to the O.K.
Corral in Tombstone, Wyatt Earp is taught that nothing
matters more than family and the law.
Joined by his brothers and Doc Holliday, Earp wages war
on the dreaded Clanton and McLaury gangs.
Wyatt Earp, played by Kevin Costner.
Doc Holliday, played by Dennis Quaid.
Nicholas Earp, played by Gene Hackman.
James Earp, played by David Andrews.
Morgan Earp, played by Linden Ashby.
Ike Clanton, played by Jeff Fahey.
Wyatt Earp is a 1994 American epic biographical Western
drama film about the lawman of the same name.
Directed by Lawrence Kasdan, who co-wrote the screenplay with Dan Gordon, the film follows Earp
from his early life to his career as a marshal and his involvement in the O.K.
Corral gunfight.
It features an ensemble cast led by Kevin Costner as Earp, with Gene Hackman, Mark Harmon, Michael Madsen, Bill Pullman,
Dennis Quaid, Isabella Rossellini, Tom Sizemore, JoBeth Williams, and Mare Winningham in supporting roles.
The film was developed in competition with Tombstone,
another adaptation of Earp's life and the O.K.
Corral gunfight that came out six months earlier.
Released on June 24, 1994, Wyatt Earp received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the performances and
Kasdan's direction, but criticized the three-hour runtime and unfavorably compared it to Tombstone.
It was a box office failure, grossing $55.9 million on a $63 million budget.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, sheriff,
gambling, deputy sheriff, arizona.
The tone is emotional.